人的接觸
Human touch.
我們第一次的交流
Our first form of communication.
安全、放心、舒適
Safety, security, comfort,
這一切都在手指溫柔的愛撫中
all in the gentle caress of a finger.
或是從嘴唇到柔軟臉頰上的笑容
Or the brush of lips on a soft cheek.
我們的快樂與之聯繫在一起
It connects us when we're happy,
在恐懼的時候 支持我們
bolsters us in times of fear,
在激情時刻 讓我們興奮
excites us in times of passion
還有愛
and love.
我們需要所愛之人的接觸
We need that touch from the one we love
幾乎就和我們需要呼吸一樣重要
almost as much as we need air to breathe.
但我從沒辦法了解 接觸有多重要
But I never understood the importance of touch.
他的觸摸
His touch.
目前為止我都沒辦法得到它
Until I couldn't have it.
哦！
Oh!
哦 好
Oh, yeah.
哦 真是的 這件真漂亮
Oh, yeah. This one's perfect.
事實上 儘管棕褐色線條可能讓人覺得難以置信
Actually, though, the tan lines might be incredible.
哦 天哪 它連你一半的胸都遮不了了
Oh, my gosh. That doesn't even cover half your boob.
這個真的很可愛
This is actually cute.
確實是很可愛
that's actually really cute.
我看一下
Let me see.
我喜歡這個
I like that.
哦 是的 它真的很漂亮
Oh, yeah, that's actually really pretty.
但我不能告訴你 是不是太騷包了
But I can't tell, is it too trampy
還是不夠騷包？
or not trampy enough?
你好!
Hello!
你要和我們一起去嗎？
Are you with us?
好吧 猜猜看
Okay, guess what.
泰勒和梅森正要和我們見面
Taylor and Mason are meeting us
早上在機場
at the airport in the morning.
那張臉是怎樣？
What's that face?
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
我知道 我知道 我知道！
I know. I know, I know!
兄弟 梅森和布魯克分手了
Dude, Mason and Brooke broke up.
不 他們沒有
No, they didn't.
哦 天哪！瑪雅！
Oh, my God! Maya!
你一定能成功的！
You're gonna do it!
我希望我能親自去那裏看看
I wish I could be there to see that in person.
你今年的計劃真糟糕
Just sucks that you planned it this year
你甚至都不能去
and you don't even get to go.
好
Well,
你可以用你的PS軟體把我合上去
you can just Photoshop me in with your fancy editing apps.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
你知道我在說什麼
You know what I'm talking about.
你為什麼笑？不 我沒有
Why are you laughing? No, I don't.
還可以去掉你長粉刺的地方
The one where you get your pimples
還有你那小小的假腮紅
and your little fake blush.
閉嘴
Shut up.
睫毛！你的睫毛在現實生活中並不長
The lashes! Your lashes aren't that long in real life.
你們真煩人
You guys are so annoying.
好吧 來吧 謝謝你的漢堡
Okay, come on. Thank you for the burgers.
說實話 你們會玩得很開心的
Honestly, you guys are gonna have so much fun.
好嗎？
Okay?
再見 我愛你
Bye. I love you.
我更愛你
I love you more.
我愛你
I love you.
想念你 再見.
Miss you. Bye.
親親 做好安全措施
Mwah. Use protection.
謝謝 ﻿媽媽
Thanks, Mom.
你好，世界
Hallo,World
所以 我又回到醫院了
So, I am back in the hospital again
再調高一次
for another tune-up.
我還需要幾輪的抗生素
I need a few more rounds of antibiotics
為了克服這個小小的喉嚨痛
to get over this little sore throat
我一直…
that I've been...
嗨 芭比！
Hi, Barb!
喉嚨痛？
Sore throat?
是的 和102度發燒？
Right, with a 102 fever?
我更糟了 說你好！
I've had worse. Say hi!
斯特拉 把那東西從我臉上拿開
Stella, get that thing out of my face.
你看起來不錯！
You're looking good!
斯特拉會在我們把她安排好後馬上回來
Stella will be right back after we get her all set up.
你們聽到女老闆的話了
You heard the boss lady.
我認為這是她最好的創作了
I think this is her best work.
哇嗚
Wow.
哇嗚 過去六個月發生了很大的變化
Wow. A lot's changed in the last six months.
是的
Yep.
他會在三月份預產
He's due in March.
請彎下你的手
Bend your arm, please.
波伊在哪個房間？
What room's Poe in?
310.
打開
And open up.
好的
All right.
你們都準備好了
You are all set.
一會兒見
I'll see you in a bit.
謝謝你 朱莉
Thank you, Julie.
哇嗚
Wow.
你確定這樣可以嗎？
Are you sure this is okay?
我還是會繼續監視你的
I will still be monitoring you.
是的 沒關係
And, yes, it's okay.
沒有你我該怎麼辦？
What would I do without you?
你會死的
You'd die.
那是真的
That's true.
所以 芭比讓我繼續保持著
So, Barb is letting me keep
這次我的醫療車在我的房間裏
my med cart in my room this time.
她給我留下了一堆藥片
And she left me a bunch of pills,
一些調理果汁
some G-Juice.
好喝！那是營養液
Yum! That's the liquid nutrition
直接到我的胃
that goes straight to my stomach
通過我的胃管
through my G-tube.
所以 對你們任何一個女孩來說
So, to any of you girls out there
你們希望你一天能吃5000卡路里
wishing you could eat 5,000 calories a day
一磅也不能多
and not gain a pound,
我隨時都可以和你交換
I'll trade you any day.
今天我可能會重新籌劃這件事
Today I'll probably be reorganizing this thing
因為你們很多人都知道 我有點怪癖
because as many of you know, I'm slightly anal.
我說的怪癖是指臨床上的強迫症
By slightly anal, I mean clinically OCD.
所以 世界和平
So, peace.
再見 夥伴們
Bye, guys.
樓上有新生嬰兒誕生了
New baby upstairs.
到15樓見我
Meet me in 15.
嗨 辛西婭
Hi, Cynthia.
嗨 斯特拉
Hi, Stella.
你好
Hi.
我早已經記下護士的時間表了
I've already clocked the nurse's schedule,
所以除非你把屁股坐在那個呼叫按鈕上
so unless you plant your ass on that call button,
一個小時內沒有人會打擾你
no one's gonna bother you for, like, an hour.
嘿 我還得睡那張床 好嗎？
Hey. I gotta sleep on that bed, okay?
真的 我是說 我們不是動物
Wow. I mean, we're not animals.
別擔心 不會花那麼長時間的
Don't worry, it's not even gonna take that long.
嘿！威利斯 你到底在說什麼？
Hey! Whatchu talkin' about, Willis?
好的 再見
Okay, bye.
看到你正在搬你的東西
Saw you moving in your stuff.
是的 呃…
It was, uh...
有很多東西
There was a lot of it.
你要在這裏待一陣子嗎？
Are you gonna be here for a while?
哈囉？
Hello?
哦
Oh.
你聾了
You're deaf.
你不應該在你的房間拉皮條的
Shouldn't you be procuring your room
給你的訪客？
for your guests?
你是按小時出租還是什麼？
You rent by the hour or what?
所以 那是你埋伏在大廳裏
So, that was you lurking in the hall.
嗯 我沒有埋伏 而是你跟著我來了
Mmm, I don't lurk, and you followed me here.
我本來想自我介紹一下
I wanted to introduce myself,
但你的態度有點…
but that little attitude of yours...
讓我猜猜看 你就是那種人
Let me guess. You're the kind of guy
從來就無視規矩的
that ignores the rules
因為它讓你覺得自己可以掌控一切 我說的沒錯吧？
'cause it makes you feel in control. Am I right?
你沒有錯
You're not wrong.
你覺得那很可愛嗎？
You think that's cute?
你覺得它很可愛嗎？
Do you think it's cute?
讓你的朋友借你的房間做愛
Letting your friends borrow your room for sex
很噁心 所以 不
is disgusting, so, no.
你不喜歡性嗎？
You don't like sex?
不 我喜歡
No, I like
性 我喜歡性
sex. I like sex.
性很好
Sex is fine.
好並不是一個響亮的認可
Fine isn't exactly a ringing endorsement,
但我會找一些共同點 我可以找到的
but I'll take some common ground where I can get it.
我們沒有共同點
We have nothing in common.
哦 真冷漠
Ooh, that's cold.
什麼 你上來在這幹嘛？
What... What are you doing up here?
任何時候都要保持6英尺距離 你們應該都知道規則
Six feet at all times. You both know the rules.
威爾 回你房間去
Will, get back to your room.
又來了
There you go.
你的心理印象裡已經有一個小名字了
A little name for your psychological profile.
我是威爾·紐曼
I'm Will Newman.
你呢？
And you are?
聾啞人士
Deaf.
斯特拉 謝謝你戴上你的面罩
Stella, thank you for putting your mask back on.
斯特拉
Stella.
你需要放鬆一下
You need to lighten up.
這就是生活
It's just life.
在你知道之前就結束了
It'll be over before you know it.
那麼 他是個CF患者？
So, he's a CFer?
洋蔥伯克氏菌
B. cepacia.
新藥物試驗對象的一員
Part of a new drug trial for Cevaflomalin.
你簽了合同 你就可以…
You contract that and you can...
你就可以親吻未知數新的肺說並說再見了
You can kiss the possibility of new lungs goodbye.
細菌不會再回來了
There's no coming back from that bacteria.
永遠遠離
Stay away.
你好 世界
Hello, world.
好吧 呼吸道確保設備再過30分鐘
Okay, AffloVest for 30 more minutes,
那你就準備好了
then you're all set.
在我上路之前你還需要什麼嗎？
You need anything else before I hit the road?
兩個巧克力布丁？
Chocolate pudding for two?
哦 那又怎麼樣？我現在是客房服務嗎？
Oh, so, what? I'm room service now?
必須利用這些額外的好處
Gotta take advantage of the perks.
好的
All right.
好女孩 好女孩
Good girl, good girl.
好的 很好 正確的
All right, good. Right.
好的 親愛的
Right, sweetie.
明天見
I'll see you tomorrow.
再見 芭比
Bye, Barb.
好的
Okay.
像所有囊性纖維化的孩子一樣
Like all kids with cystic fibrosis,
我生來就是終結者
I was born terminal,
這並不代表著我明天就要死了
which doesn't necessarily mean I'm gonna die tomorrow,
但我也可能明天就會死
but I could die tomorrow.
明天誰都可能會死
Anyone could die tomorrow.
我只是比別人的時間少了一點
I just have a little bit less time
所以機率比其他人都多
than everyone else.
我的肺現在大約有50%的功能
My lungs are at about 50% function right now.
所以以這個速度
So at this rate,
哈米德醫生說我需要移植
Dr. Hamid says that I'll need a transplant
在我高中三年級的時候
by the time I'm a junior in high school.
那會很有趣的
That'll be fun.
嗨 夥計們！噓！
Hi, guys! Shh!
我們在新生兒加護中心
We're at the NICU
因為我對嬰兒著迷
because I'm obsessed with babies.
還有芭比…
And Barb...
美麗的芭比給予我許可
The beautiful Barb is giving me permission
讓我現在一個人進來
to come in here by myself now.
如你所知 囊性纖維化是一種遺傳疾病
Cystic fibrosis, as you know, is a genetic disease
這基本上使我的身體產生大量的粘液
that basically makes my body produce a shit ton of mucus.
有趣的是 我必須非常小心
Fun fact, I have to be extremely careful
和其他CF患者相處在一起
around other people with CF.
規則是我們不可以
The rule is that we're not
待在虛構的六英尺以內
supposed to get within six feet
因為我們最終會
because we could end up
傳染彼此的細菌
catching each other's bacteria.
很多人沒有意識到就算換上新的肺
A lot of people don't realize that new lungs
一般也只能持續五年生命左右
generally only last about five years,
但其實沒關係 因為實際上我們大多數人
which is okay actually because most of us
只是想試著活得夠久
are just trying to stay alive long enough
所以有了一種新的治療方法
for a new treatment to come out.
就只是在我的新呼吸道確保設備裡放鬆
Just chilling here in my new AffloVest,
這真的很酷
which is really cool
因為現在我不必掛在牆上
because now I don't have to be hooked up to the wall,
很明顯我不是
which obviously I'm not
因為我倒掛在床上
because I'm hanging upside down on my bed.
這真的很好
This is actually good
把粘液弄出來之類的
for getting the mucus up and stuff.
我知道 可愛 對吧？
I know, cute, right?
當當 女孩
Dang, girl.
你看起來很疲憊
You look worn.
這男的是誰？
Who is he?
還是我認識的人嗎？
Is it anyone I know?
你早餐得到了什麼？
What'd you get?
什麼？
What?
這些是松露嗎？你怎麼弄到松露的？
Are those truffles? How'd you get truffles?
哦 你得自己帶它們來 姊妹
Oh, you gotta bring them with, sister.
哇嗚
Wow.
看看那輛餐車有多火辣
Look at how spicy that food cart is.
我印象深刻
I'm impressed.
好吧 我們談談我
All right, let's talk about me.
我現在單身！
I'm single!
你和邁克爾分手了？
You broke up with Michael?
也許是他和我分手了
Maybe he broke up with me.
是嗎？
Did he?
這是互相的
It was mutual.
不 不是的
No, it wasn't.
為什麼？你真的很喜歡他
Why? You actually really liked him.
我以為他會是那個人
And I thought he was gonna be the one.
他顯然不是
He obviously isn't.
不管怎麼說都要去殺了他 對吧？
Screw him anyway, right?
至少你得這麼做
At least you got to do that.
波伊？
Poe?
波伊 你還好嗎？
Poe, you okay?
嗆咳 310病房
Choking, 310.
對不起 朱莉
I'm sorry, Julie.
我的腿碰到了呼叫按鈕
My leg hit the call button.
你嚇到我們了 波伊
You scared us, Poe.
是的 下次試試咀嚼
Yeah, try chewing next time.
這裏 斯特拉
Here, Stella.
享受你的松露吧 混蛋
Enjoy your truffles, asshole.
並且請小心
And please be careful.
我愛你 斯特拉
I love you, Stella.
第一階段臨床試驗
Phase one clinical trials
只在18個月前開始
only started only 18 months ago,
所以我們需要耐心
so we need to be patient
威爾需要幫助我們
and Will needs to help us with that.
現在交叉感染的風險會更高 所以…
The risk of cross infection will be even higher now, so...
別對著其他相同CF患者咳嗽
Don't cough on any other CFers.
好吧 別靠他們太近
Well, don't get close enough to touch them
為了他們和你的安全
for their safety and yours.
任何時候都是保持6英尺 我明白
Six feet at all times. I got it.
威爾 為了交代好這個工作
Will, in order for this to work,
你需要跟上你的療程
you need to keep up with your regimen.
好的 我很快就會再見到你
Okay, I will see you soon.
你穿著泳衣！
You're wearing the bathing suit!
你好！
Hi!
哦 我正式嫉妒了 看起來很有趣！
Oh, I'm officially jealous. That looks so fun!
我們想念你！
We miss you!
我也很想你！
I miss you, too!
你有可愛的男孩訪客嗎？
You have any cute boy visitors?
不 不 他不可愛
No. No. He's not cute.
什麼？
What?
男孩？
Boy?
什麼？
What?
快秀給我們看！快秀給我們看！
Show us! Show us!
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
你有遺願嗎？
Do you have a death wish or something?
嘿！
Hey!
我的肺都烤乾了 好嗎？
My lungs are toast, okay?
你能讓我盡情享受這景色嗎？
Can you just let me enjoy this view while I can?
你知道你能在這裏有多幸運嗎？
Do you know how lucky you are to be here?
參加這個藥物試驗？
To be a part of this drug trial?
你怎麼知道我的藥物試驗？
How do you know about my drug trial?
你一直在打聽我？
You been asking about me?
呃
Ugh.
如果你不在乎
If you don't care,
那就離開吧
then leave.
把你的位置讓給別人
Give your spot to someone else.
想要它的人 想要活下去的人
Someone that wants it, that wants to live.
可以
Okay.
你在幹什麼？威爾？
What are you doing? Will?
威爾 拜託你停下來！
Will, stop, please!
拜託馬上下來！
Please get down now!
威爾 停！哦 天哪！
Will, stop! Oh, my God!
天哪！
God!
放輕鬆！
Relax!
好的
Fine.
那就待在這裏吧
Stay up here then.
拜託 就只是個玩笑
Come on. It was a joke.
嘿 這只是個玩笑
Hey, it was a joke.
該死的！
Damn it!
你的醫療車和藥片呢？
Where's your med cart, and your pills,
為什麼你的呼吸道確保設備在地板上？
and why's your AffloVest on the floor?
可以…我能看看你的療程嗎？
Can... Can I see your regimen?
喔 這些都不是你的事…
Uh... Not that it's any of your business...
這是……什麼？
Is this... What?
為什麼會…
Why would...
動脈瘤看起來就是這樣嗎？
Is this what an aneurysm looks like?
為什麼？呸！
Why? Ugh!
聽著 我知道你有一些
Look, I get that you have some kind of
拯救世界英雄情結
save-the-world hero complex going on,
但你能讓我離開那情結裡嗎？
but can you leave me out of it?
這些藥物不是可選的
These meds are not optional.
是的 這可能就是為什麼
Yeah, that's probably why
他們不斷地把它們從我的喉嚨裏擠下去
they keep shoving them down my throat.
你讓我發瘋了
You're making me crazy.
嘿
Hey.
斯特拉 快點！
Stella, come on!
六英尺！
Six feet!
我需要你遵循你的療程
I need you to follow your regimen
請嚴格而完整地完成
strictly and completely, please.
為什麼不…
Why don't...
你為什麼不告訴我到底發生了什麼？
Why don't you tell me what's going on, actually?
跟我說話 我不會開玩笑也不會笑
Talk to me. I'm not gonna make any jokes or laugh.
我有強迫症
I have control issues.
我要知道一切都很順利
And I need to know that things are in order,
我知道你沒有做治療
and I know that you're not doing your treatments
真的 真的把我搞得一團糟
and it's really, really messing me up.
好吧 我想幫你
Okay, I wanna help you.
我願意
I do.
我甚至不知道怎麼做才是你要我做的
I don't even know how to do what you're asking me to.
那是胡說八道！
That's bullshit!
那是胡說！所有CF患者都知道
That's bullshit! All CFers know
如何管理自己的療程
how to administer their own treatments.
到12歲時 我們就已經是醫生了
We're practically doctors by the time we're 12.
你是認真的嗎？
Are you serious?
我真的把你搞砸了嗎？
Am I actually messing you up?
對
Yes.
好的
All right.
我會幫助你的
I'll help you.
但如果我這樣做了
But if I do,
對我有什麼好處？
what's in it for me?
不 不是你想的那樣…
No, not like...
我…我想畫你
I... I wanna draw you.
不.
No.
為什麼不？我是認真的
Why not? I'm serious.
不.
No.
好吧
Okay.
那交易就談不成了
Then no deal.
你真的就不能只練習一點紀律
You really can't practice just a little bit of discipline
即使是為了拯救自己的生命？
even to save your own life?
斯特拉 沒有什麼能挽救我們的生命
Stella, nothing is going to save our lives.
我們呼吸的是借來的空氣
We're breathing borrowed air.
享受它
Enjoy it.
好吧
Fine.
但我不會連續幾個小時擺姿勢
But I'm not posing for hours on end.
你的療程 我們按我的方式來做
And your regimen, we're doing it my way.
好吧 你要做的第一件事就是
Okay, the first thing you're gonna do
在你的房間裏放一輛醫療車 成交嗎？
is get a med cart in your room. Deal?
成交
Deal.
握一下手？
Shake on it?
好笑
Funny.
倒霉！
Shit!
哦 天哪 不 不 不！
Oh, God, no, no, no!
嘿
Hey.
你錯過了表演
You missed the show.
是啊 你在裏面做特技？
Yeah. You doing stunts in there?
是啊 沒有更好的地方可以摔斷你的腿
Well, there's no better place to break a leg.
這還算公平
That's fair.
我是威爾
I'm Will.
我是波伊
I'm Poe.
洋蔥伯克氏菌
B. cepacia.
該死 這太悲慘了
Damn, that's rough.
是啊
Yeah.
所以，沒有肺能給我移植
So, no lung transplant for me.
你什麼時候簽的合同？
When did you contract it?
大約八個月前 它很快就開始拓展開了
About eight months ago now. It colonized so quickly.
我在移植名單上待了一分鐘 然後就…
I was on the transplant list one minute and then...
我敢肯定 這種態度正是讓斯特拉這麼適合的原因
I'm sure that attitude is what's giving Stella fits.
是的 這態度怎麼了？
Yeah, what's up with that?
她告訴我她有強迫症的問題
She told me that she has control issues or something.
不管你怎麼說 她都要一起遵照她的指示
Call it what you want, she's got her shit together.
她讓我保持絕對一致的療程
She definitely keeps me in line.
所以 呃
So, uh,
你們兩個…
have you two...
不.
No.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我從七歲開始就認識那個女孩的
I've known that girl since I was, like, seven.
我不知道 夥計
I don't know, man.
聽起來你愛她
Sounds like you love her.
當然 我愛她
Of course, I love her.
那麼 你為什麼不做些什麼呢？
So, why haven't you done anything about it?
因為
Because
她不是他
she's not a he.
別擔心 我不喜歡白人
Don't worry. I don't like white boys.
哈米德醫生說你突然
Dr. Hamid said that you suddenly
想為自己的療程負責
wanna be responsible for your own regimen.
別讓我後悔
Don't make me regret this.
你把所有東西都擦乾淨了嗎？
Did you wipe everything down?
對 這不是我的主意 你知道嗎？
Yes. This wasn't my idea, you know?
我們還沒被發現吧？
Are we still clear?
對 快點
Yes. Hurry up.
我快做完了
I'm almost done.
可以 你的醫療車都準備好了
Okay. Your med cart's all set up.
我為慢性病開發了一個應用程序
I built an app for chronic illnesses.
它會提醒你什麼時候該做什麼事
It'll alert you when to do
你的治療 吃藥…
your treatments, and take your pills...
建立了一個應用程序？
Built an app?
就像是你創造的？
Like you built it?
驚訝吧
Surprise.
很簡單
It's pretty simple.
你應該能搞清楚
You should be able to figure it out.
好的 斯特拉
Okay, Stella.
別告訴我你這時候樂在其中
Don't tell me that the one time you're interested
在某個傢伙身上 他是個CF患者
in some guy, he's a CFer.
我只是剛剛幫他搭好了醫療車
I just helped him set up his med cart.
那個…就是這樣 這就是全部！
That... That's it. That's all!
我了解你 斯特拉
I know you, Stella.
幫忙組織醫療車就像前戲
Organizing a med cart is like foreplay.
他們被稱為禮貌！
They're called manners!
你有戴上你的呼吸道確保設備嗎？
Are you doing your AffloVest?
是啊
Yeah.
拍給我看
Show me.
我不能 我半裸著
I can't. I'm half-naked.
你現在應該戴上你的呼吸道確保設備的
You're supposed to be doing your AffloVest right now,
你吃了你的膠囊了嗎？
and did you take your Creon?
這些是栓劑嗎？
Are those the suppositories?
可以
Okay.
好吧 我不能相信你
Okay, I can't trust you,
所以這就是它的運作方式
so this is how it's gonna work.
我們要一起治療
We're gonna do our treatments together
所以我要知道你真的有在做這些
so that way I know you're actually doing them.
可以嗎？
Okay?
妳總是在尋找方法
Always looking for ways
能多一些時間跟我相處 不是嗎 斯特拉？
to spend more time with me, aren't you, Stella?
再見.
Bye.
我小時候就開始做這個了
I've been doing this since I was a little kid.
所以你就把它們全倒在布丁裏
So you just pour them all in the pudding
攪拌一下 你跟著做了嗎？
and stir it around. Are you doing that?
晚安
Good night.
離婚飲食看起來對你並不好 媽媽
The Divorce Diet doesn't look good on you, Mom.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
你太瘦了 而爸爸需要洗澡
You're too thin. Dad needs a bath.
你們在偷學我的外表
You guys are stealing my look.
我偷學妳的外表？
I'm stealing your look?
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
好吧 也許我比你更需要這個
Okay, maybe I need this more than you do.
不！
No!
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
那是怎麼發生的？
How did that happen?
這是怎麼發生的？
How did it happen?
哦 夥計！
Oh, man!
把餐巾紙給我
Give me napkins.
噢 親愛的
Aw, here, honey.
我非常愛你
I love you so much.
我知道 我也愛你
I know. I love you, too.
我不知道沒有你我會怎麼做
I don't know what I'd do without you.
感覺如何？
How does it feel?
不太好
Not great.
讓我們嘗試用一些巴氏桿菌
Let's try some Bactroban,
看看一兩天後會怎麼樣
see how it looks in a day or two.
也許我們可以清除乾淨 嗯？
Maybe we can clear it up, huh?
哦 我去健身房
Oh. I'll be at the gym.
謝謝 醫生！
Thanks, Doc!
嘿 你知道 這太糟了
Hey, you know, this sucks.
我們的這筆交易何時才可以變得互惠互利？
When does this deal of ours become mutually beneficial?
我做了你要求的一切
I've done everything you've asked
我的投資沒有回報
with no return on my investment.
你真的想在我們健身後畫我嗎？
You really wanna draw me after we work out?
是啊
Yeah.
不.
No.
我很噁心 出汗 還有氣味
I'm gross, and sweaty, and smell.
"我的頭髮很髒
"My hair is dirty.
"我太累了
"I'm too tired.
"我的醫療車很亂
"My med cart is messy."
好的
Fine.
那我會流更多汗的 只為你
I'll sweat harder then. Just for you.
我要把汗都畫出來
I'm going to draw that sweat.
那是什麼？
What's that?
我的待辦事項清單
My to-do list.
做清單？
To-do list?
對於那些會構建應用程序的人來說 這是相當過時的
That's pretty old-fashioned for someone that builds apps.
是的 好吧 應用程序裡面沒有給我
Yeah, well, the app doesn't give me
很滿意的運作
the satisfaction of doing
那
that.
你的任務清單上還有什麼？
What else is on that to-do list of yours?
我的主列表還是我的每日列表？
My master list or my daily list?
是的 當然你還有分兩張清單
Yeah, of course you have two lists.
主列表 這是大事 對吧？
The master list. That's the big stuff, right?
好吧
Okay.
在一場重要的政治運動中做志願者
Volunteer in an important political campaign.
完成
Done.
學習莎士比亞的所有作品
Study all the works of William Shakespeare.
完成
Done.
與其他人分享我對CF的所有瞭解
Share everything I know about CF with other people.
這是我的YouTube網頁
That's my YouTube page.
所以 你的計劃是死得很聰明
So, your plan is to die really smart
這樣你就可以加入
so that you can join
死者的辯論隊還是什麼？
the debate team of the dead or something?
環遊世界怎麼樣？
What about traveling the world?
學彈鋼琴
Learn to play piano.
完成
Done.
說流利的法語
Speak fluent French.
你能看我一會兒嗎？
Can you look at me for a sec?
你想聽我的清單嗎？
You wanna hear my list?
不.
No.
和鮑勃·羅斯一起上繪畫課
Painting class with Bob Ross.
他死了
He's dead.
是的 沒關係 嗯哼...
Yeah, never mind. Uh...
在梵蒂岡做愛
Sex in the Vatican.
我寧願幫你認識鮑勃·羅斯
I'd rather help you meet Bob Ross.
我不知道
I don't know.
我想環遊世界
I'd like to travel the world.
事實上 最好去看看
Actually get to see some of it
而不是這些醫院的內部的景色
and not the inside of these hospitals.
謝謝您
Thank you.
為了什麼？
For what?
因為你說的有一部份很真實
For saying something real.
是梵蒂岡的事嗎？
Was it the Vatican thing?
你能快點嗎？
Can you hurry up?
可以 我只是想讓你知道
Okay. I just thought you might want to know
感覺如何 準備好了嗎？
how this feels. You ready?
我帶來了一個跳躍夥伴
And I brought a jumping buddy.
別擔心 我會緊緊地抱著他
Don't worry. I'll hold him tight.
好了 艾比 準備好跳下飛機了嗎？
All right, Abby, ready to jump out of a plane?
準備好了！
Ready!
生日快樂 斯特拉
Happy Birthday, Stella.
我愛你 斯特拉 很快再見
I love you, Stella. I'll see you soon.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
我喜歡看到你這樣
I like seeing you like this.
像什麼？
Like what?
充滿希望
Hopeful.
好的
All right.
嘿 朱莉
Hey, Julie.
如果這不起作用怎麼辦？
What if this doesn't work?
如果有呢？
What if it does?
哈哈！
Ha-ha!
為什麼是漫畫？
Why cartoons?
它們具有顛覆性
They're subversive.
他們可以是輕快和有趣的 但合起來可以帶來一個強大的衝擊
They can be light and funny but pack a powerful punch.
我想畫得很好的漫畫
I think a well-drawn cartoon
比言語更能表達
can say a lot more than words ever could.
是啊？
Yeah?
這到底意味著什麼？
What does this say exactly?
就是能比言語多得多
A lot more than words ever could.
我覺得其實很不錯
I think it's actually pretty good.
我覺得那很好 在你身後
I think that's really good. Behind you.
那是什麼？
What is that?
哦 那是肺 太棒了
Oh, those are lungs. That's brilliant.
你做的嗎？
Did you do that?
不 我姐姐艾比
Uh, no, my older sister, Abby.
真的 她真的很厲害
Wow. She's really good.
我想多看看她的東西 你還有嗎？
I'd love to see more of her stuff. Do you have any?
我們不必 呃 分享我們的故事 好嗎？
We don't have to, uh, share our stories, okay?
我們可以一起做治療
We can just do our treatments together.
嘿 夥計們！我要買一個鼻整形器…
Hey, guys! I have to get a nasal poly...
息肉切除術
Polypectomy.
我們正在切除你鼻腔的息肉
We're removing polyps from your nasal passages.
斯特拉很緊張
And Stella's nervous.
但我會在那兒唱歌到她入睡
But I'm gonna be there to sing her to sleep.
一如既往
Just like always.
我愛你一蒲式耳一啄
♪ I love you A bushel and a peck ♪
一蒲式耳一啄
♪ A bushel and a peck ♪
別唱整首歌
Don't sing the whole thing yet.
抱著脖子
♪ And a hug around the neck ♪
你會搞砸的
You're gonna jinx it.
一桶一堆
♪ And a barrel and a heap ♪
你會搞砸的
You're gonna jinx it.
我正在睡夢中談論你
♪ And I'm talkin' in my sleep About you ♪
但是認真
But seriously.
你睡覺的時候我會在那兒的
I'm gonna be there when you go to sleep
你醒來的時候我就在這裏
and I'm gonna be right here when you wake up.
可以嗎？
Okay?
可以
Okay.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
我姐姐 艾比 女士們先生們
My sister, Abby, ladies and gentlemen.
順便說一下 她還是單身
She's single, by the way.
她的年齡是…
Her digits are...
那是去年
That was last year.
在那之後艾比沒有出現在任何視頻中
Abby's not in any of the videos after that.
我找到艾比的IG了
I found Abby's Instagram.
我是說 這主要都是關於藝術
I mean, it's mostly art,
她和斯特拉 但你是對的
her and Stella, but you're right.
我是說 她一年沒有更新了
I mean, she hasn't posted in a year.
芭比沒看見你進來 是嗎？
Barb didn't see you come in, did she?
沒有.
No.
艾比死了 是嗎？
Abby's dead, isn't she?
你真是個小笨蛋
You're as delicate as a jackhammer.
史黛拉 我們沒有時間品嚐美食 我們快死了
We don't have time for delicacy, Stella. We're dying.
你能不能別提醒我我快死了？
Can you stop reminding me that I'm dying?
我明白了 我明白了
I get it. I get that.
可以？我就是不能
Okay? I just can't.
我一輩子都在等待死亡
I have been dying my whole life.
每一個生日 我們都像慶祝我最後一個生日一樣的慶祝
Every birthday, we celebrated it like it was my last one.
- 我知道 我也是 – 不 你不知道
- I know. Me, too. -No,you don’t know
因為那時 是的 正如你指出的 艾比死了
Because then, yeah, as you pointed out, Abby died.
然後我父母的婚姻也就死了
And then my parents' marriage died.
本來應該是我
And it was supposed to be me.
大家都準備好了
Everyone was ready for that.
每個人都為此做好了準備
Everyone was prepared for that.
我只是 我不能死
I just, I can't die.
我只是…我的父母…我不能
I just... My parents... I can't.
這就是為什麼你如此沉迷於你的療程？
Is this why you're so obsessed with your regimen?
你不怕死 你有倖存者的罪惡感
You're not afraid of dying. You have survivor's guilt.
威爾？
Will?
你是一個有著倖存者罪惡感的生病女孩
You're a sick girl with survivor's guilt.
這是你無法控制的
This is out of your control.
我別無選擇 好嗎？
I just don't have any other choice, okay?
是的 但這正是我想告訴你的
You do. But that's what I'm trying to tell you.
我不！威爾 我不想
I don't! Will, I don't.
好的 斯特拉 嘿 對不起
Okay, Stella. Hey, I'm sorry.
我們應該繼續冥想的
We're supposed to be meditating.
斯特拉 快點！
Stella, come on!
你知道他有邊緣化的問題
You knew he had boundary issues.
不管怎樣 我認為他無意傷害你
For what it's worth, I don't think he meant to hurt you.
是的 但還是很煩人
Yeah, but it's still annoying.
他說「艾比」和「死了」
Like, he said "Abby" and "dead"
在同一句話裏出現 好像沒什麼大不了的
in the same sentence like it was no big deal.
我應該去那兒
I should've been there.
斯特拉 看看我
Stella, look at me.
你不知道
You can't know.
你就是不能
You just can't.
不要再這樣對自己說了
Stop told your self.
哦 這種病就是監獄
Oh, this disease is a prison.
我想擁抱你
I wanna hug you.
假裝我現在正在做
Just pretend that I'm doing it right now.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
你想要冰淇淋嗎？
You wanna get ice cream?
好
Yes.
如果感染進入血液…
If the infection gets into the bloodstream...
嘿
Hey.
一切都會好起來的
It's gonna be okay.
你不知道
You don't know that.
你說得對 我不知道 這很危險
You're right. I don't. It's risky.
但是膿毒症是更大的怪物
But sepsis is the bigger monster.
嘿
Hey.
你是個鬥士 斯特拉·格蘭特
You're a fighter, Stella Grant.
你一直都是
You always have been.
所以…
So...
是嗎？
Yeah?
是啊
Yeah.
那麼明天早上
Tomorrow morning, then.
我會通知你父母的
I'll let your parents know.
嘿
Hey.
你在這裏
You're here.
我在這裏
I'm here.
我拿到你的漫畫了 你被原諒了 退後
I got your cartoon. You're forgiven. Back up.
你錯過了我們的治療 發生什麼事？
You missed our treatment. What's going on?
胃管感染了
Infected G-tube.
哈米德醫生擔心膿毒症
Dr. Hamid's worried about sepsis,
所以她要在早上進行替換手術
so she's replacing it in the morning.
我在這個情況下只能服從了
I'm going under general.
倒霉
Shit.
你的肺還好嗎？
Are your lungs up for that?
你的霧化器8點會到 還有你的呼吸道確保設備，好嗎？
Do your nebulizer at 8:00, and your AffloVest, okay?
你在這裏幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
老實說 我以為這是浴室
I thought this was the bathroom, honestly.
這是你沒有艾比的第一次手術
It's your first surgery without Abby.
你怎麼知道的？
How do you know that?
我看過你所有的視頻
I've seen all your movies.
有些人可能會說
Some might say
我是你最大的粉絲
I'm your biggest fan.
所以 我真的希望我不要搞砸了
So, I really hope that I don't mess this up.
我愛你一蒲式耳一啄
♪ I love you A bushel and a peck ♪
一蒲式耳 一啄一啄 摟住脖子
♪ A bushel and a peck And a hug around the neck ♪
走開！走開！
Go away! Go away!
抱著脖子 抱著桶 抱著堆
♪ A hug around the neck And a barrel and a heap ♪
一桶一堆
♪ A barrel and a heap ♪
我正在睡夢中談論你
♪ And I'm talkin' in my sleep About you ♪
我們奶奶過去常給我們唱這首歌
Our grandma used to sing that to us.
我不得不用谷歌搜索 它真的很舊
I had to Google it. It's really old.
我知道
I know.
到底是什麼
What the heck's
一桶一堆？
a barrel and a heap?
你會沒事的
You're gonna be okay.
你保證？
Promise?
嘿
Hey.
你準備好開始了嗎？
You ready to get this show on the road?
是啊
Yeah.
哦 該死 不！
Oh, hell, no!
威爾！
Will!
她在害怕
She was scared.
我只是想做點好事
I just wanted to do something nice.
拜託！
Come on!
她在麻醉下更危險
She's in more danger under the anesthesia
比她和我在一起要慘
than she is with me.
特雷弗
Trevor Von.
這就是你讓我想起的人
That's who you remind me of.
特雷弗·馮和艾米·普雷斯利
Trevor Von and Amy Presley.
哦 他們是…
Oh, they were...
他們相愛了
They were in love.
我讓他們打破規則 讓他們快樂
And I let them break the rules so they could be happy.
讓我猜猜
And let me guess,
他們死了？
they died?
是的 威爾 他們做到了
Yes, Will, they did.
在我的監視下
On my watch.
如果我再讓這種事發生 我會被詛咒的
And I'd be damned if I let that happen again.
一切都會好起來的
It's gonna be okay.
你知道該怎麼做
You know what to do.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
十 九…
Ten, nine...
…八
...eight,
七…
seven...
噓…
Shh...
哦
Oh...
嗨 是我
Hi, it's me.
打電話給我 因為我想你 好嗎？
Call me 'cause I miss you, okay?
但別打電話給我 因為我剛從手術室出來
But don't call me, 'cause I just got out of surgery
而且我真的很累
and I'm really tired.
但當你收到這個的時候還是給我打電話
But call me though when you get this,
因為你很可愛
because you're cute
我想見你
and I wanna see you
還有你蓬鬆的小頭髮
and your fluffy little hair
還有你瘦小的腿
and your little skinny legs.
可以嗎？
Okay?
不過別打電話給我
Don't call me, though,
因為如果我聽到你性感的聲音
because if I hear your sexy voice,
我會睡不著 所以…
I won't be able to sleep, so...
收到後給我打電話 好嗎？
Call me when you get this, okay?
再見.
Bye.
威爾不來了
Will's not coming.
威爾？
Will?
你不開門我就不走
I'm not leaving until you open the door.
我不能
I can't.
只是 請打開門 我們可以談談關於這個
Just, please open the door and we can talk about this.
好嗎？我不管芭比說什麼
Okay? I don't care what Barb said.
把門打開！
Just open the door!
我不能
I can't.
威爾 拜託
Will, come on.
走開 斯特拉
Go away, Stella.
也許這樣更好
Maybe it's better this way.
不 我能搞清楚
No, I can figure this out.
我需要弄清楚
I need to figure this out.
我們不是普通的孩子
We're not normal kids.
我們不能像這樣冒險
We don't get to take chances like this.
哦 來吧 你也不會給我那個嗎？
Oh, come on. You're not gonna give me that, too?
承認這裏發生了什麼
Admit what's going on here.
威爾是個冒險者 就像艾比一樣
Will's a risk-taker, just like Abby.
那是什麼意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
你認為我害怕冒險？
You think that I'm the one that's afraid to take risks?
你和你的生活又是怎麼樣
What about you and your life
你的關係呢？
and your relationships?
你和蒂姆 你和裏克 你和邁克爾
You and Tim, you and Rick, you and Michael.
不要講到那裏去
- 我要繼續講
Don't go there.
I want to keep going to talk
他們知道你病了 他們愛你
They knew you were sick and they loved you.
是你跑走的 每次 都是你自己跑走的
You were the one who ran. Every time, you ran.
你不知道你在說什麼
You don't know what you're talking about.
你毀了你所擁有的每一次戀愛的機會
You ruined every chance you've ever had at love,
所以你只要把你的建議留給自己就行了
so just keep your advice to yourself.
婊子
Bitch.
混蛋
Asshole.
你知道 你是對的
You know, you're right.
我很害怕
I am afraid.
你知道有人愛我會得到什麼結果嗎？
You know what someone gets for loving me?
他們得支付我所有的醫療費用
They get to pay for all my care.
然後他們必須看著我死去
And then they get to watch me die.
免賠額、藥物、住院、手術
Deductibles, meds, hospital stays, surgeries.
當我滿18歲的時候 就再也沒有全面的保險了
When I turn 18, there's no more full coverage.
我該依賴誰？
Who should I put that on?
邁克爾還是我的家人？
Michael or my family?
這是我的病 這是我的問題
It's my sickness, it's my problem.
也許我們可以讓威爾娶你
Maybe we can get Will to marry you.
他很有錢
He's loaded.
他不挑的 他喜歡你
He's not picky. He likes you.
我很抱歉
I am sorry
關於你和威爾
about you and Will.
斯特拉？
Stella?
什麼？
What?
斯特拉？
Stella?
哈囉
Hello.
有點不一樣
There is something a little bit different
我今天想談談
I want to talk about today.
頭孢伯克霍爾德菌
Burkholderia cepacia.
風險和限制
The risks, the restrictions
以及交戰規則
and the rules of engagement.
頭孢是一種耐寒的細菌
B. cepacia is a hardy bacteria.
好嗎？它是如此有高適應性的
Okay? It is so adaptive
它確實以青黴素為食
that it literally feeds on penicillin.
所以 我們的第一道防線是
So, our first line of defense is
醫院級手部消毒器
Cal Stat, a hospital-grade hand sterilizer.
經常大量使用
Apply liberally and often.
下一個是好的老式乳膠手套！
Next is good old-fashioned latex!
是真的
Tried-and-true.
用於保護所有類型的活動
Used for protection in all types of activities.
頭孢類在唾液或痰中最為活躍
B. cepacia thrives best in saliva or phlegm.
有趣的是 咳嗽能散播的距離是6英尺
Fun fact, a cough can travel six feet,
打噴嚏的速度可達每小時200英里
a sneeze can travel up to 200 miles per hour.
但是「沒有唾液」的東西也意味著沒有親吻
But the "no saliva" thing also means no kissing.
永遠
Ever.
所以 我們最好的防守就是距離
So, our best defense is distance.
任何時候都保持6英尺
Six feet at all times.
塔達！
Ta-da!
這是檯球提示
Here's a pool cue.
它長約5英尺
It measures approximately five feet.
剛好5英尺
Five feet.
我對第六步考慮了很久
I've given a lot of thought to foot number six.
你知道嗎？這讓我很生氣
And you know what? It made me mad.
當你有囊性纖維化的時候 很多都會從你身上帶走
When you have cystic fibrosis, so much is taken from you.
你生活的每一天
You live every day of your life
根據療程、藥片和時間表
according to treatments, and pills, and schedules.
我們大多數人不能有孩子
Most of us can't have children.
我們很多人甚至活得不夠長
A lot of us don't even live long enough
想要孩子
to try to have children.
該死 解釋起來很複雜
Shit, it's complicated to try to explain,
但更難墜入愛河
but it's even hard to fall in love.
所以 在這個疾病偷了我這麼多錢之後
So, after all that CF has stolen from me,
從我們這裏
from us,
我不介意偷點東西回來
I don't mind stealing a little something back.
一步的距離
One foot.
他媽的就一步
One fucking foot
空間 距離
of space, of distance,
長度 或者隨便你想怎麼稱呼它
of length, or whatever you wanna call it.
我不介意偷回去
I don't mind stealing that back.
因為CF.…
Because CF...
不再只有你能當小偷了
you're not the thief anymore.
我現在也是小偷了
I'm the thief now.
相距五英尺
Five feet apart.
成交嗎？
Deal?
你加入嗎？
Are you in?
我完全加入
I'm so in.
中庭 9:00
Atrium. 9:00.
我為什麼不收拾好東西？
Why didn't I pack anything nice?
哦 因為你總是帶著火熱的醫院式浪漫
Oh, 'cause you always pack for a hot hospital romance.
這是透明的嗎？
Is this see-through?
別想了 呵呵
Don't even think about it, ho.
你好
Hi.
我出生的時候他就逃走了
He cut and ran when I was born.
我想生個生病的孩子不是他的計劃
I guess having a sick kid wasn't part of his plan.
你媽媽呢？
What about your mom?
她很漂亮 很有幹勁 很聰明
She's beautiful and driven and smart.
她只關注我和我一個人
She's just focused on me and me alone.
所以 從明天開始 當我滿18歲的時候
So, starting tomorrow, when I'm 18,
我將為自己做決定
I will be making the decisions for myself.
等等 等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
明天是你的生日？
Tomorrow's your birthday?
你本來可以告訴我的
You could have told me that.
我沒有給你的禮物
I don't have a present for you.
你答應下一次留下來怎麼樣？
How about you just promise to stick around for the next one?
來吧
Come on.
我要離開這裏
I'm getting out of here.
我喜歡這個理論
There is this one theory I like
那就是說 「要理解死亡 你必須關注出生 」
that says, "To understand death, you have to look at birth."
所以 像
So, like,
當我們在子宮裏的時候 我們就過著這樣的生活
while we're in the womb, we're living that existence
不知道我們的下一個存在
not knowing that our next existence
只有一英吋遠
is just an inch away.
所以 也許死亡也一樣
So, maybe it's the same with death.
也許死亡只是下一個生命
Maybe death is just the next life,
但一英吋遠
but an inch away.
或者只是像睡了個大覺 寶貝
Or maybe it's just a big sleep, baby.
熄燈
Lights out.
完成和完成
Done and done.
不.
No.
沒有辦法
There's no way
艾比只是眨了眨眼
that Abby just blinked out.
我拒絕相信
I refuse to believe it.
艾比怎麼了？
What happened with Abby?
她在加利福尼亞州跳崖
She was cliff diving in California.
她摔倒了 摔斷了脖子淹死了
She landed wrong, broke her neck and drowned.
他們說她沒有感覺到任何疼痛
They said she didn't feel any pain,
但他們怎麼知道她是否感到疼痛呢？
but how would they know if she felt pain?
我本來應該和她在一起的 但我生病了
I was supposed to be there with her, but I got sick.
就像我一直做的
Like I always do.
我只是一遍又一遍地想像
I just keep imagining it over and over again.
她當時的感覺
What she was feeling.
不知道這一點 她就不會停止死亡
Without knowing that, she just never stops dying.
斯特拉
Stella.
即使你在那裏 你仍然不知道
Even if you were there, you still wouldn't know.
但我不在那裏
But I wasn't there.
她獨自死去
She died alone.
那不是我們要死的方式嗎？
Isn't that how we're gonna die?
溺水 只是沒有水
Drowning. Just without the water.
我們自己的黏液完成這個髒活
Our own fluids doing the dirty work.
我經常想起最後一次大口的呼吸
I think about that last breath a lot.
喘氣
Gasping for air,
一點也吸不到
not getting any.
任何的空氣
No air,
只是一片黑
just black.
但那只是星期一
But that's only on Mondays.
除此以外 我就不想糾結在這上面了
Otherwise, I don't dwell on it.
就是那個微笑
There's that smile.
天哪 你真漂亮
God, you're beautiful.
勇敢
And brave.
我希望我能碰你
I wish I could touch you.
我撒了謊
I lied
當我們相遇的時候
when we met.
我從未發生過性行為
I've never had sex.
我從不想讓任何人看到我
I've never wanted anyone to see me.
身上的傷疤 呃
The scars, uh,
管子 沒有人會覺得這些性感的
the tube, nothing about it's sexy.
你的一切都很性感
Everything about you is sexy.
我覺得你很完美
I think you're perfect.
早安
Good morning.
看到外面的燈了嗎？
See those lights out there?
艾比和我叫他們星星
Abby and I would call them stars
我們會許願的
and we would make wishes.
她從不告訴我她的願望是什麼
She'd never tell me what her wish was,
但我知道她希望我有新的肺
but I knew she wished for new lungs for me.
我希望她能如願以償
I hope she gets her wish.
是的 我也是
Yeah, me too.
早安 芭比
Mornin', Barb.
他們在哪裏？
Where are they?
誰？
Who?
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
哦 完蛋了 芭比知道我們走了
Oh, shit. Barb knows we're gone.
好吧
Okay.
呃 她會先在新生兒加護中心找我 所以…
Uh, she'll look for me first in the NICU, so...
再見!好的
Bye! Okay.
我自由了！
I'm free!
哦
Oh...
哦 天哪！
Oh, my gosh!
生日快樂！
Happy Birthday!
我很抱歉 我忘了
I'm so sorry. I forgot.
不 沒有關係
No, it's fine.
你在幹什麼？你忙嗎？我們去散散步吧
What are you doing? Are you busy? Let's take a walk.
我現在不行
I can't right now.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我正在學習
Studying.
也許晚一點？
Maybe later?
我的朋友們實際上要晚些時候來
My friends are actually coming later.
沒關係
That's all right.
我們會再想辦法的
We'll figure something out.
我只是 呃
I was just, uh,
想念你
missing you.
晚點再跟你談
Talk to you later.
好的 再見.
All right. Bye.
傑森
Jason.
是的 不 別…
Yeah, no. Don't...
不 別擔心 沒關係的
No. Don't worry about it. It's fine.
不 說真的 我沒有生氣
No, seriously, I'm not mad.
很好 去忙你的事
It's fine. Just do your thing.
我明天再和你談談
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
以為你永遠找不到我
Thought you'd never find me.
我知道很晚了
I know it's late,
但我們不得不等到自助餐廳關門
but we had to wait till the cafeteria closed.
「我們」？
"We"?
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
驚喜！
Surprise!
我們對拋棄你感到很難過 夥計
We felt so bad for ditching you, dude.
但你女朋友告訴我們
But your girlfriend DM'd us
說服我們給你驚喜 夥計
and convinced us to surprise you, man.
「女朋友」？
"Girlfriend"?
你太棒了
You're so good.
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
我不敢相信他是真的
I can't believe he's real.
我知道！
I know!
而且他本人更性感
And he's even hotter in person.
說真的
Seriously.
嘿 食物快準備好了！
Hey, the food's almost ready!
祝你生日快樂！
And Happy Birthday!
只是想在工作中觀察主人
Just wanted to observe the master at work.
那些是玫瑰嗎？
Are those roses?
它們真漂亮
They're so beautiful.
你是怎麼做到的？
How do you do that?
我一直在練習
I've been practicing.
因為下個月 邁克爾和我
'Cause next month, Michael and I
要去見我媽媽
are gonna go see my mom.
真的？
Really?
他明天來吃午飯 我會一起去吃
He's coming to lunch tomorrow and I'm gonna go for it.
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
他愛我
He loves me.
我也愛他
And I love him, too.
哦 波伊 我太高興了！
Aw, Poe, I'm so happy!
拜託別對著我多愁善感
Don't go all soppy on me.
你知道我沒辦法讓一個女孩獨自哭泣
You know I can't let a girl cry alone.
他們是幸福的眼淚
They're happy tears.
我為你高興 波伊
I'm happy for you, Poe.
讓我們吃吧！
Let's eat!
波伊 你從哪兒弄來的？
Poe, where did you get all of this?
醫院有VIP廚房
Hospitals have VIP kitchens
他們把所有的好東西都放在那裏
where they keep all the good stuff.
你知道 對於名人和政治家來說
You know, for celebrities, politicians.
但今晚 生日男孩 是給你的
But tonight, Birthday Boy, it's for you.
慶祝！
Salud!
我們是 就像 十個！
We were, like, ten!
對 我們把床單放在頭上
Yes. And we literally put sheets over our head
然後跑進癡呆病房！
and ran into the dementia ward!
就像那樣！
It was just like that!
哇嗚！
Woo!
這太瘋狂了
It was crazy.
這是有史以來最好的萬聖節！
It was the best Halloween ever!
我們遇到了很多麻煩
We got in so much trouble.
這甚至不是我們的主意
And it wasn't even our idea.
記得嗎？艾比…是艾比想出了這個主意
Remember? Abby... Abby came up with that.
艾比很狂野
Abby was wild.
她總是為所欲為
She was free.
她總是說她會活得很好
She always said she was gonna live big
因為斯特拉不能
because Stella couldn't.
她做到了
She did.
她生活得很好
She lived big.
比我們任何人都好
Bigger than any of us.
她會喜歡秘密聚會的
She would've loved a clandestine party
就像這個！
like this one!
她會的
She would've.
敬艾比
To Abby.
祝你生日快樂！額
♪ Happy Birthday to you! ♪
哇！
Whoo!
許個願！
Make a wish!
我不能把蠟燭吹滅 否則你們不能吃
I can't blow the candles out or else you guys can't eat it.
我向你許願
I made a wish for you.
謝謝您
Thank you.
一個 二
One. Two.
好的
All right.
哎呀！
Yay!
生日快樂 威爾！
Happy Birthday, Will!
芭比？
Barb?
嘿！
Hey!
我們以為你今晚不在
We thought you were off tonight.
你要我們給你裝個盤子嗎？
You want us to fix you a plate?
就是這樣 就是這樣
That's it. That's it.
你們都被限制在房間裏
You're all confined to your rooms
而我們進行呼吸培養
while we get respiratory cultures.
而你
And you.
你將在早上被調離這裡
You'll be transferred in the morning.
芭比！芭比 這不是他的錯
Barb! Barb, it wasn't his fault.
好吧 你可能願意用你的生命來賭博
Well, you might be willing to gamble with your lives,
但我不行！
but I'm not!
這就像我們小時候一樣而已
Just like when we were kids.
但你不再是孩子了 波伊
But you're not kids anymore, Poe.
但我們像你教我們的那樣安全
But we were safe like you taught us to be.
哦
Oh.
對不起 不過很有趣！
I'm sorry, but it was fun!
好吧 我讓你睡覺 好嗎？
All right, I'm gonna let you go to sleep, okay?
晚安
Good night.
來點提神的？
A little pick-me-up?
謝謝您
Thank you.
他走了就更安全了
It's just safer if he goes.
你可能是對的
You're probably right.
她會恨我的
She's gonna hate me.
嗯嗯 嗯
Mmm-hmm.
怎麼了 波伊？
What's up, Poe?
他可能又坐到呼叫按鈕上了
He probably sat on the call button again.
我去看看
I got it.
敲門 敲門 波伊？
Knock, knock. Poe?
藍色代碼！
Code Blue!
注意 所有醫務人員
Attention, all medical personnel.
波伊！波伊！
Poe! Poe!
波伊！
Poe!
沒有脈搏
No pulse.
哦 天哪！可以
Oh, God! Okay.
跟我在一起 寶貝
Stay with me, baby.
他沒有呼吸 他沒有呼吸
He's not breathing. He's not breathing.
來吧 你能做到的 來吧
Come on, you can do it. Come on.
把他包起來 開始胸部按壓！
Bag him. Start chest compressions!
加油！
Come on!
給他注射腎上腺素！
Give him an Epi!
來吧 寶貝！
Come on, baby!
這是一個嚴重的張力性氣胸
It's a massive tension pneumothorax.
他的肺在衰竭！
His lung is collapsing!
把墊子放在他身上！把墊子放在他身上！
Put the pads on him! Put the pads on him!
拜託 夥計
Come on, buddy.
來吧 親愛的 快點 親愛的！
Come on, sweetie. Come on, sweetie!
快點 夥計！
Come on, buddy!
芭比 怎麼了？
Barb, what's happening?
來個人把她弄出去！
Somebody get her out of here!
關上門！
Close that door!
芭比 怎麼了？
Barb, what's happening?
哈米德博士？
Dr. Hamid?
現在不行 斯特拉
Not now, Stella.
哈米德博士？
Dr. Hamid?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
不！
No!
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不！
No!
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
哦 天哪！他走了！
Oh, my God! He's gone!
邁克爾再也見不到他了
Michael's never gonna see him again.
他的父母再也見不到他了
His parents are never gonna see him again.
我再也見不到他了
I'm never gonna see him again.
我從未擁抱過他！
I never hugged him!
他是我最好的朋友 我從來沒有擁抱過他！
He's my best friend and I never fucking hugged him!
哦 天哪！
Oh, God!
我失去了所有人
I'm losing everyone.
你不會失去我的
You're not losing me.
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
走開！
Get out!
滾開！
Just get out!
我想去看燈光
I wanna go see the lights.
好像在兩英里外
It's gotta be, like, two miles away.
嘿 來吧 我們進去吧
Hey, come on, let's go inside.
跟我來
Come with me.
斯特拉 現在不是叛逆的時候
Stella, now's not the time to be rebellious.
這是因為波伊嗎？
Is this about Poe?
是因為波伊的
It is about Poe.
是關於艾比的 是關於你和我的
It's about Abby, it's about you and me
和所有我們永遠不能一起做的事情
and all the things that we'll never get to do together.
一直以來 我都在為我的治療而活著
This whole time, I've been living for my treatments
而不是做我的治療 這樣我才能活下去
instead of doing my treatments so that I can live.
我想活下去
I wanna live.
這只是活著 威爾
It's just life, Will.
在我們了解之前就結束了
It'll be over before we know it.
好吧
All right.
我們至少能坐計程車去嗎？
Can we catch a cab at least?
我想散步 享受夜晚
I wanna walk and enjoy the night.
手套 我們很好
Glove. We're good.
你怎麼總是讓我鍛煉？
How are you always getting me to exercise?
從上面看肯定更好
Sure looks better from up here.
那是什麼？
What's that?
沒錯 你得解釋一下這東西
Yeah, you're gonna have to explain that one.
艾比給我買的
Abby got it for me
在我第一次來醫院的時候
the first time I came to the hospital.
從那次以後 我每次都帶著它
I've had it with me every time since.
說實話 這是一種解脫
That's a relief, honestly,
因為我沒有勇氣告訴你
'cause I didn't have the heart to tell you
再第三次犯愚蠢的錯誤我們可能就玩完了
that a third boob might be a deal breaker.
嘿 斯特拉
Hey, Stella.
嗯？
Hmm?
天很冷
It's cold.
來吧
Come on.
我們去看看你的燈
Let's go see your lights.
讓我們休息一下吧
Let's take a breather.
斯特拉？嘿 別這樣
Stella? Hey, don't do that.
斯特拉
Stella.
它是結冰的固體
It's frozen solid.
嘿 女士們
Hey, ladies.
我剛接到堪薩斯城聖盧克的電話
I just got a call from St. Luke's in Kansas City.
有發生死亡的車禍
Car accident with fatalities.
一個女性 AB血型5'2「 胸腔大小…
One female, AB neg, 5'2", thoracic cage size...
斯特拉有肺了
Stella's getting lungs.
預計三小時 讓她做好準備
ETA three hours. Get her prepped.
哦 我的上帝
Oh, my God.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
不 不 不 不 不 不！
No, no, no, no, no. No!
唷！
Whew!
嘿
Hey.
沒事吧？
Everything all right?
是啊
Yeah.
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
哦！
Oh!
我愛你 斯特拉
I love you, Stella.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
我們不能
We can't.
我知道
I know.
斯特拉
Stella.
哦
Oh...
倒霉！
Shit!
快點 快點！
Come on, come on!
來吧
Come on.
芭比 芭比？芭比
Barb. Barb? Barb.
她沒有回答
She's not answering,
現在直接轉到語音信箱
and now it's going straight to voicemail.
斯特拉永遠不可能逃跑 她不會那樣做的
Stella would never run off. She wouldn't do that.
你能聯繫到他嗎？
Have you been able to reach him?
不.
No.
他們走了多久了？
How long have they been gone?
如果你兒子讓斯特拉失去這些肺…
If your son causes Stella to lose these lungs...
我兒子和你女兒一樣病重
My son is just as sick as your daughter is.
斯特拉絕不會做這種事
Stella would never do anything like this.
她永遠不會這麼做
She's never done anything.
斯特拉做了 艾琳
Stella did this, Erin.
不是威爾 他對新肺的事一無所知
Not Will. He doesn't know anything about the lungs.
肺？
Lungs?
有移植手術嗎？
Is there a transplant?
是的 移植給斯特拉 他們在路上了
Yeah, for Stella. They're on the way.
好吧 至少告訴我你是個愛貓的人
Well, tell me at least you're a cat person.
你喜歡貓嗎？
Do you like cats?
我有一隻雪貂
I owned a ferret.
我是一個雪貂小孩
I was a ferret kid.
哦 不 你會是一個雪貂小孩
Oh, no. You would be a ferret kid.
不要回答
Don't answer it.
真的？他們現在需要什麼？
Really. What do they need right now?
是我媽媽
It's my mom.
讓我告訴她我沒事
Let me just tell her that I'm okay.
斯特拉 他們有新的肺給你
Stella, they have new lungs for you.
嘿 他們有新的肺給你
Hey, they have new lungs for you.
我們去醫院吧 快走！
Let's go to the hospital. Come on!
我還沒看到燈光
I haven't seen the lights yet.
燈光？
The lights?
你已經知道了嗎？我們還在外面幹什麼？
Did you know about this? What are we doing out here?
我們回去醫院吧
Let's go to the hospital.
來吧
Come on.
為了多活五年？
Five years?
對我們這樣的人來說 五年是一生
Five years is a lifetime for people like us.
不是這樣的！因為發生了什麼
It's not! Because what happens
當他們失敗了 我又回到了原地？
when they fail and I'm back to square one?
別傻了 我們能回去醫院嗎？
Let's not be stupid. Can we go the hospital, please?
來吧 我們走
Come on, let's go.
斯特拉！
Stella!
斯特拉
Stella.
來吧
Come on.
拜託？很冷耶
Please? It's cold.
斯特拉！
Stella!
斯特拉
Stella.
救命！
Help!
來吧 斯特拉
Come on, Stella.
快點！
Come on!
快點 斯特拉
Come on, Stella.
我們有一個17歲的孩子…
We have a 17-year-old...
我們現在有什麼？
What have we got?
17歲女性囊性纖維化
A 17-year-old female with cystic fibrosis.
我們已經為她準備好了肺
We already have lungs for her.
有人能摘下另一個面罩嗎？
Can someone get the other mask off?
哦 我的上帝 親愛的
Oh, my God. Honey.
沒關係
It's okay.
我的兒子 我兒子也在外面
My son. My son was out there, too.
我很抱歉 請後退一步
I'm sorry. Step back, please.
你沒事 你沒事
You're okay. You're okay.
威爾在哪裏？
Where's Will?
親愛的
Honey.
走過來！
Coming through!
他還好嗎？
Is he okay?
請盡快給她戴上口罩
Get a mask on her as soon as possible, please.
O2到45
O2 is at 45.
可能體溫過低
Possible hypothermia.
我們需要更多的毯子
We're gonna need more blankets over here.
呼吸就好了 斯特拉？
Just breathe. Stella?
我抓住你了 親愛的
I've got you, honey.
斯特拉？
Stella?
你需要冷靜下來
You need to calm down.
我們有你的新肺
We have your new lungs.
是的 斯特拉
Yes, Stella.
我不想要新肺了
I don't want them.
斯特拉 我們已經等這些肺好幾年了
Stella, we've been waiting for these lungs for years.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
如果你不使用肺 它們就浪費了 親愛的
If you don't use the lungs, they're wasted, sweetie.
我愛他 但有了這個新肺
I love him. The new lungs
沒有他什麼意義都沒有
won't mean anything without him.
躺下！
Lay down!
住手！住手！
Stop! Stop!
拜託!停下來
Please! Stop.
威爾！
Will!
拜託
Please.
接受這個新肺
Take the lungs.
為了我
For me.
好吧
Okay.
來吧 戴上面罩
Come on, put the mask on.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
好吧 好吧 我們開始進行吧 大家
Okay, all right, let's go, everyone.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
好的 我們開始吧 我們要移動床位了
Okay, here we go. We're moving.
我馬上就到 親愛的
I'll be right here, honey.
走吧
Let's go.
好吧 我非常愛你
Okay, I love you so much.
我愛你 爸爸
I love you, Dad.
好的 我們開始吧
Okay, here we go.
哈米德博士
Dr. Hamid.
我跟她嘴對嘴了
I gave her mouth-to-mouth.
我很抱歉 我別無選擇
I'm sorry. I didn't have any other choice.
你救了她的命 威爾
You saved her life, Will.
如果她有洋葱伯克氏菌 我們會處理的 好嗎？
If she has B. cepacia, we'll deal with it, okay?
細菌培養結果回來了
Bacterial cultures came back.
我不知道為什麼 但她很乾淨
I don't know how, but she's clean.
她還沒被感染到
She didn't get it.
但這並不意味著她不會再被感染
But that doesn't mean she won't.
威爾呢？
What about Will?
治療有效嗎？
Is the treatment working?
不.
No.
不 它沒有
No, it's not.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
為了所有的這些
For all of this.
不 不 不 不 親愛的
No, no, no, no, sweetie.
這不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
媽媽 嘿
Mom. Hey.
嘿 媽媽
Hey, Mom.
什麼？怎麼了？怎麼了 親愛的？
What? What is it? What is it, honey?
你能幫我做些事情嗎？
Could you help me with something?
你們加入嗎？
Are you guys in?
當然
Absolutely.
芭比？
Barb?
見鬼 是的 我加入吧
Hell, yeah, I'm in.
她體內還有鎮靜劑 我們還有幾個小時
She's sedated. We have a few more hours.
我們有時間
We have time.
搞定了
It's done.
他們答應了
They said yes.
可以
Okay.
讓我們這樣做
Let's do this.
我已經做了所有我要做的 威爾 我完成了
I've done all I'm doing with this, Will. I'm done.
謝謝您
Thank you.
她醒了
She's waking up.
嘿 親愛的
Hey, honey.
嘿 親愛的 你做得很好！
Hey, sweetie, you did great!
你真的做到了
You really did.
你做得很好
You did great.
你做得很好 寶貝
You did wonderful, baby.
你做得很好
You did good.
沒關係
It's okay.
我們有東西給你
We have something for you.
我美麗的 蠻橫的斯特拉
My beautiful, bossy Stella.
我想這是真的 你那本書是怎麼說的
I guess it's true, what that book of yours says.
靈魂知道沒有時間了
That the soul knows no time.
我的藥物試驗不起作用
My drug trial's not working.
我想讓你知道這一個月
I want you to know that this past month
將永遠為我而存在
will last forever for me.
我唯一遺憾的是
My only regret is that
你沒有看到你的燈
you didn't get to see your lights.
我終於讓你啞口無言了
I finally got you speechless.
你知道 人們總是說如果你愛某件事
You know, people are always saying if you love something,
你必須學會放手
you have to learn to let it go.
我以為那是胡說八道
I thought that was such bullshit.
直到我看到你快死了
Till I watched you almost die.
在那一刻 斯特拉
In that moment, Stella,
對我來說什麼都不重要了
nothing mattered to me.
除了你
Except you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不想離去
I don't wanna go.
我只想和你在一起
All I want is to be with you.
但我不能
I can't.
我需要讓你安全
I need you to be safe.
聽我的話吧
From me.
我不知道接下來會發生什麼,
I don't know what comes next,
但我對此並不後悔
but I don't regret any of this.
你能閉上眼睛嗎？
Could you close your eyes?
我只是不知道我能不能好好走開
I just don't know if I can walk away
如果你還在看著我
if you're still looking at me.
拜託
Please.
我愛你
I love you
非常
so much.
他把這個留給你了
He left this for you.
（威爾的未完成清單列表:第一條 - 永遠愛斯特拉）
WILL’S MASTER LIST -No.1 LOVE STELLA FOR EVER
人的接觸
Human touch.
我們的第一種交流方式
Our first form of communication.
安全、放心、舒適
Safety, security, comfort,
所有的一切都在一個手指的溫柔愛撫中
all in the gentle caress of a finger.
或是從嘴唇到柔軟臉頰上的笑容
Or at the brush of lips on a soft cheek.
嘿 斯特拉 你不能錄下來 不.
Hey, Stella. You can't record that. No.
當我們快樂的時候 它將我們聯繫在一起…
It connects us when we're happy...
艾比  不!
Abby, no.
…在恐懼的時候支持我們…
...bolsters us in times of fear...
你能把那個關掉嗎？
Can you turn that off?
…在激情時刻讓我們興奮…
...excites us in times of passion...
啊 不 斯特拉 不 停下！
Ah. No. Stella, no. Stop!
……還有愛
...and love.
我們需要我們所愛的人的那種觸摸
We need that touch from the one we love
幾乎和我們需要呼吸的空氣一樣多
almost as much as we need air to breathe.
但我從未理解觸摸的重要性
But I never understood the importance of touch.
他的觸摸
His touch.
目前為止我都沒辦法得到它
Until I couldn't have it.
所以 如果你在看這個影片
So, if you're watching this
而你可以的話
and you're able,
摸摸他
touch him.
撫摸她
Touch her.
生命太短 不能浪費一秒鐘
Life's too short to waste a second.